Good morning. So magic is an excellent way
صباح الخير.السحر طريقة ممتازة
for staying ahead of the reality curve,
للبقاء في طليعة منحنى الواقع،
to make possible today
لنجعل من الممكن اليوم
what science will make a reality tomorrow.
ما سيجعل منه العلم حقيقة غدا.
As a cyber-magician, I combine elements of illusion
وكساحر سيبراني، أدمج عناصر الوهم
and science to give us a feel of how future technologies
والعلم لإعطائنا فكرة عن كيف يمكننا اختبار
might be experienced.
التكنولوجيات المستقبلية.
You've probably all heard of Google's Project Glass.
قد تكونون جميعا قد سمعتم ربما بمشروع نظارات غوغل.
It's new technology. You look through them
إنها تكنولوجيا جديدة. تنظر من خلالها
and the world you see is augmented with data:
والعالم الذي ترونه معزز بالبيانات:
names of places, monuments, buildings,
أسماء الأماكن والمعالم والمباني،
maybe one day even the names of the strangers that pass you on the street.
وفي يوم ربما، ربما حتى أسماء الغرباء الذين تمرون بهم في الشارع.
So these are my illusion glasses.
إذن فهذه نظاراتي للوهم.
They're a little bigger. They're a prototype.
إنها أكبر قليلا. إنه نموذج أولي.
And when you look through them, you get a glimpse
وحين تنظر من خلالها، تلقي نظرة خاطفة
into the mind of the cyber-illusionist.
على ذهن مخادع سيبراني.
Let me show you what I mean.
دعوني أريكم ما أعنيه.
All we need is a playing card. Any card will do.
كل ما نحتاجه هو ورقة لعب. أي ورقة ستفي بالغرض.
Like this. And let me mark it so we can recognize it
كهذه. دعوني أضع علامة عليها حتى نتمكن من التعرف عليها
when we see it again.
حين نراها مجددا.
All right. Very significant mark.
حسنًا. علامة كبيرة جداً.
And let's put it back into the deck,
ودعونا نعدها إلى الحزمة،
somewhere in the middle, and let's get started.
في مكان ما في الوسط، ودعونا نبدأ.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Voice: System ready. Acquiring image.
الصوت: النظام جاهز. جاري الحصول على الصورة.
Marco Tempest: For those of you who don't play cards,
ماركو تمبست: لمن منكم لا يلعبون بالبطاقات،
a deck of cards is made up of four different suits:
أوراق اللعب تتكون من أربع منظومات مختلفة:
hearts, clubs,
القلوب الحمراء والشجر
diamonds and spades.
والكومي والقلوب السوداء.
The cards are amongst the oldest of symbols,
البطاقات هي من بين أقدم الرموز،
and have been interpreted in many different ways.
وقد تم تفسيرها بطرق مختلفة كثيرة.
Now, some say that the four suits
الآن، يقول البعض أن المجموعات الأربعة
represent the four seasons.
تمثل الفصول الأربعة.
There's spring, summer,
هناك فصل الربيع، والصيف،
autumn and —
الخريف و
Voice: My favorite season is winter.MT: Well yeah, mine too.
صوت: الفصل المفضل لدي هو الشتاء.م. ت: نعم، هو مفضل لدي كذلك.
Winter is like magic. It's a time of change,
فصل الشتاء هو مثل السحر. إنه وقت تغيير،
when warmth turns to cold, water turns to snow,
عندما يتحول الدفء إلى برد، والماء إلى ثلج،
and then it all disappears.
ومن ثم يختفي كل شيء.
There are 13 cards in each suit. (Music)
وهناك 13 بطاقات في كل مجموعة. (موسيقى)
Voice: Each card represents a phase of the 13 lunar cycles.
صوت: كل بطاقة تمثل مرحلة من الدورات القمرية الـ13.
MT: So over here is low tide,
م. ت: لذا هنا نرى الجزر،
and over here is high tide,
وهنا نرى المد،
and in the middle is the moon.
والقمر في الوسط.
Voice: The moon is one of the most potent symbols of magic.
صوت: القمر واحد من الرموز الأقوى للسحر.
MT: There are two colors in a deck of cards.
م. ت: هناك لونان في ورق اللعب.
There is the color red
هناك اللون الأحمر
and the color black,
واللون الأسود،
representing the constant change
ممثلة التغيير المستمر
from day to night.
من اليوم إلى الليل.
Voice: Marco, I did not know you could do that. (Laughter)
صوت: ماركو، لم أكن أعرف أنه بإمكانك فعل ذلك. (ضحك)
MT: And is it a coincidence that there are 52 cards
م. ت: ومن قبيل الصدفة أن هناك 52 بطاقة
in a deck of cards, just as there are 52 weeks in a year?
في ورق اللعب، تماما كما أنه هناك 52 أسبوعا في السنة؟
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Voice: If you total all the spots on a deck of cards,
صوت: إن قمتم بإضافة البقع على بطاقات ورق اللعب مجتمعة
the result is 365.
النتيجة هي 365.
MT: Oh, 365, the number of days in a year,
م. ت: أوه، 365، عدد الأيام في سنة،
the number of days between
عدد الأيام بين
each birthday.
كل عيد ميلاد.
Make a wish. (Blowing noise)
تمنّ. (صوت نفخ)
Voice: Don't tell, or it won't come true.
صوت: لا تخبرني، وإلا فلن تتحقق.
MT: Well, as a matter of fact, it was on my sixth birthday
م. ت: حسنا، في الواقع، لقد كان عيد ميلادي السادس
that I received my first deck of cards,
حين تلقيت أول بطاقات لعب،
and ever since that day, I have traveled around the world
ومنذ ذلك اليوم، سافرت إلى جميع أنحاء العالم
performing magic for boys and girls,
لتأدية عروض سحرية للأولاد والبنات،
men and women, husbands and wives,
للرجال والنساء والأزواج والزوجات،
even kings and queens. (Applause)
حتى الملوك والملكات. (تصفيق)
Voice: And who are these?MT: Ah, mischief-makers. Watch.
صوت: ومن هؤلاء؟م. ت: آه، مثيروا الشغب. راقبوا.
Wake up.
استيقظ.
Joker: Whoa.MT: Are you ready for your party piece?
جوكر: وا.م. ت: هل أنت مستعد لدورك في الحفلة؟
Joker: Ready!MT: Let me see what you've got.
جوكر: جاهز!م. ت: دعني أرى ما لديك.
Joker: Presenting my pogo stick.MT: Ah. Watch out.
جوكر: أقدم لكم عصا البوغو الخاصة بي.م. ت: آه. احترس.
Joker: Whoa, whoa, whoa, oh! (Music)
جوكر: وا، وا، وا، أوه! (موسيقى)
MT: But today, I am performing for a different kind of audience.
م. ت: ولكن اليوم، أنا أؤدي لنوع مختلف من الجمهور.
I'm performing for you.
أنا أؤدي لكم.
Voice: Signed card detected.MT: Well, sometimes people ask me
صوت: تم الكشف عن البطاقة المعلّمة.م. ت: حسنا، أحياناً يسألني الناس
how do you become a magician? Is it a 9-to-5 job?
كيف تصبح ساحر؟ هل هي وظيفة من الساعة 9 صباحا إلى الـ5 مساء؟
Of course not! You've got to practice 24/7.
بالطبع لا! عليك أن تمارسها طوال الوقت.
I don't literally mean 24 hours, seven days a week.
لا أقصد حرفيا 24 ساعة، سبعة أيام في الأسبوع.
24/7 is a little bit of an exaggeration,
طوال الوقت فيه نوع من المبالغة،
but it does take practice. Now, some people will say,
ولكن الأمر يتطلب ممارسة. الآن، سوف يقول بعض الناس،
well, magic, that must be the work of some evil
حسنا، السحر، يجب أن يكون ذلك عمل شرير
supernatural force. (Laughter) (Applause)
قوة خارقة للطبيعة. (ضحك) (تصفيق)
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Whoa.
وا.
Well, to this, I just say, no no.
حسنا، لذلك، أنا أقول فقط، لا ولا.
Actually, in German, it's nein nein. (Laughter)
وفي الواقع، في اللغة الألمانية، إنها ناين ناين. (ضحك)
Magic isn't that intense. I have to warn you, though,
السحر ليس بتلك الكثافة. لكن علي تحذيركم،
if you ever play with someone who deals cards like this,
إن لعبتم قط مع شخص يوزع البطاقات هكذا،
don't play for money.
لا تلعب من أجل المال.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Voice: Why not? That's a very good hand.
صوت: لم لا؟ هذه يد جيدة جداً.
The odds of getting it are 4,165 to one.
احتمالات الفوز بها هي 4,165 لواحد.
MT: Yeah, but I guess my hand is better. We beat the odds.
م. ت: نعم، لكن أعتقد أن يدي أفضل. نحن نتغلب على الاحتمالات النادرة.
Voice: I think you got your birthday wish.MT: And that actually leaves me with the last,
صوت: أعتقد أنك حصلت على أمنية ميلادك.م. ت: وهذا يتركني مع آخر،
and most important card of all:
وأهم بطاقة على الاطلاق:
the one with this very significant mark on it.
تلك ذات العلامة الكبيرة جداً عليها.
And unlike anything else we've just seen,
وخلافا لأي شيء آخر قد رأيناه للتو،
virtual or not.Voice: Signed card detected.
افتراضي أم لا.صوت: تم الكشف عن البطاقة الموقعة.
Digital MT: This is without a question the real thing.
م. ت الوسائطي: هذه وبدون سؤال هو الشيء الحقيقي.
MT: Bye bye. (Music)
م. ت: وداعا وداعا. (موسيقى)
Thank you. (Applause)
شكرا. (تصفيق)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you very much. (Applause)
شكرا جزيلا. (تصفيق)